here's a question why did countries like
India and Pakistan become so poor after
colonization but places like the US
Canada and Australia became so rich is
there something wrong with Indians I'm
asking because this American YouTuber
who hates India said this oh people
saying Oh India was a colony oh it's not
their fault you know where else was a
colony the United States of America so
suck on that ah but see there you make
the classic mistake of forgetting that
the British colonizers in the US did
this teeny tiny thing called genocide on
the local population so they could
settle there these three guys are the
2024 winners of the Nobel Prize for
economics they said that in order to
maintain a strong economy you need
strong institutions education healthare
trading networks Industries if citizens
can't rely on these institutions in that
country the nation will fail
pre-colonial India was rich and had all
these institutions that we built over so
many centuries so the British slowly
dismantled our institutions replaced
High skill indust Ries with low skill
labor and basically made Indians
completely lose Faith with the Indian
way of life but in the US the British
simply wiped out the Native American
tribes either with guns or small poox
and then permanently settled the land
that's the big difference the British
never wanted to stay long-term in India
they just wanted our resources which
they then used to build shiny new cities
in the west where they set up brand new
institutions just like the ones in
Europe that's how they were able to get
so rich after colonization